MEHDI MAROUANI

Senior software engineer

Phone: (+216) 99 334 081

Email: mehdi.marouani.developer@gmail.com

Location: Bizerte, Tunisia, 7000

Website: mehdi-marouani.netlify.app
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/mehdi-marouani

GitHub: github.com/mehdi049

Upwork: upwork.com/mehdi-marouani

I am a passionate web developer with +9 years of experience creating web applications that range from simple to complex, and I am fully committed to every project. Happy to work alone or within a team as I am self-organized, a fast learner, motivated, and like to do things the right way.

Feel free to check out my Upwork profile and find out what my clients are saying about my work.

RELEVANT SKILLS

NextJS / ReactJS Redux / useContext FIGMA to web page Tailwind / Material-UI / Bootstrap Typescript Cypress Strapi GIT **API** integration Agile practices Storybook Microservice architecture SOL .Net core Entity framework / Dapper End-to-end testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Vistaprint, https://www.vistaprint.com
Senior Software Engineer – Tunis, Tunisia – (full remote)

February 2019-Present

- Assisted junior developers and implemented multiple feature-rich releases for our supply chain online business.
- Successfully led the migration of our web application from .Net framework to .Net core / ReactJS, resulting in increased performance by over 100%.
- Assisted in designing and extending our micro-service architecture resulting in fewer dependencies and 50% fast deployment.
- Collaborated with the team and the product owner to create and assign tickets for each sprint.
- Successfully reduced manual tasks for suppliers and plant users, saving the company +5k monthly.
- Assessed interviewing candidates (technical and behaviour interviews).

Junior Software Engineer – (On site)

February 2018–February 2019

- Completed assigned tasks within deadlines and demonstrated a willingness to learn new technologies.
- Enhanced the UI layout and made the web portal fully responsive, increasing client usage by 150%.
- Actively participated in Agile sprint planning, stand-ups, and retrospectives.

AllAboutOnline Web developer - Gloucester, United Kingdom - (On site)

Mars 2015-February 2017

- Converted Photoshop wireframes into a fully functional web applications.
- Met with potential clients and suggested solutions for their businesses.

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Flitter, https://www.flitter.fr

Lead front-end developer - Paris, France - (full remote)

January 2022-January 2024

- Translated Figma design wireframes into responsive interactive web pages.
- Optimized front-end code for improved performance and scalability.
- Integrated RESTful API to display dynamic content on the web application.
- Worked closely with back-end developers to implement front-end components with server-side logic.

Upwork, https://upwork.com Senior web developer

January 2021 – January 2022

Top-Rated-Plus freelancer (top 3%) with +20 projects completed successfully and 100% job success rate. link to my profile.

- Worked with different clients and several projects that ranged from a simple contact form to much more complex web applications.
- Developed a set of skills that enabled me to meet tight deadlines and handle multiple projects.

EDUCATION

Private School of Engineering and Technology – ESPRIT / Tunis, Tunisia

2012-2015

IT Engineering degree

ISET Rades / Tunis, Tunisia IT Bachelor degree

2009-2012

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent - B2

French - Fluent

Arabic - Native